杰森∶宝贝儿,我到家了.
Jason: Hi honey I'm home.
迈克:看见你真是太好了.
Mike: Good to see you too dear.
杰森∶迈克,看看你.在美好的春天的傍晚6点钟的时候,你在干什么呀?
Jason: Mike, look at you.6pm on a fine spring evening...What are you doing?
迈克∶我在吃好吃的早点呢.
Mike: I'm eating a sensible breakfast.
杰森∶你一整天都在睡觉?就这样浪费了宝贵的的8小时?
Jason: You slept the entire day away?Wasted 8 precious hours?
迈克∶那就叫晚餐好了.
Mike: Ok, call it Dinner.
杰森∶迈克,难道你希望对你一直浪费生命的事情,
Jason: Mike you expect me to just stand by and say nothing while you just
我会袖手旁观,不闻不问吗?
waste your life?
迈克∶差不多.
Mike: Pretty much.
杰森∶你打算以后怎么办?你有没有为你的将来想过?
Jason: What are you going to do about your future?Ever even think about that?
迈克∶爸爸,好了,你不必说我了.
Mike: Dad come on, you don't have to read me.
杰森∶这不是说教,这是一个父亲的忠告.
Jason: This is not reading, this is fatherly advice.
迈克∶有什么区别吗?
Mike: What's the difference?
杰森∶如果你不听从父亲的忠告的话,那我就会教训你了.
Jason: Reading is what I do if you don't take the fatherly advice.
迈克,
Mike, you are almost through with junior college.
你2年的大专学习马上就要结束了,那你下一年有什么计划?
Come on, what are your plans for next year?
迈克∶明年?爸爸,
Mike: Next year?Dad, I'm eating breakfast.
我现在正在吃早餐,我们能不能吃完午饭后,再谈这个问题?
Can't we talk about this after lunch?
杰森∶我才不会等那么久.迈克,现在就说,你明年的计划是什么?
Jason: I won't be up that long Mike.Come on what are you doing next year.
迈克∶到时就会知道了.
Mike: Something will pop up.
杰森∶到时就会知道了!
Jason: Something will pop up!
迈克∶是的.
Mike: Yes.
杰森∶迈克,什么什么什么?工作?还是继续学习?监狱?
Jason: Mike, what what what?A job?More school huh?Jail?
迈克∶好吧,那你明年的计划是什么?
Mike: All right, what are your plans for next year?
杰森∶我是父母,迈克,我们不允许去制定计划.
Jason: I'm a parent Mike..We are not allowed to make plans
开萝尔∶大事情,还是每月一训?
Carol: Something big, or just the usual monthly read?
杰森∶开萝尔,你能不能离开一下,
Jason: Carol, would you mind leaving please,
让我说完我对他的父亲的忠告.
so I can finish giving mike his fatherly advice.
开萝尔∶好,但是一定要说大声点,我可不想错过一个字.
Carol: Ok, but be sure to yell, I don't want to miss a word.
杰森∶出去!!!
Jason: Get out!!!
迈克∶爸爸,休何福乐.
Mike: Dad, Hugh Hefner.
杰森∶怎么了?
Jason: What about it?
迈克∶是一个整天穿着睡衣的很成功的男人,
Mike: A very successful man who, and you can look this up,
你可以去查查他的资料.
wears pajamas around the clock.
杰森∶时常,你都会说一些让我震惊的不行的话.
Jason: Every so often, you say something that frightens me to the core.
迈克∶爸爸,我的意思是说不能因为我睡了一整天就意味着我没有考虑过我的将来,我已经考虑过很多次了.
Mike: Dad, my point is that just because I sleep all day, does not mean
that I'm not thinking about my future.I've given it a lot of thought
杰森∶哦!是吗?
Jason: Oh yeah?
迈克∶是的,我想成为一名演员.
Mike: Yes, I'm going to be an actor.
杰森∶这就是未来?
Jason: That's a future?
迈克∶是的,爸爸,这是我的梦想.
Mike: Yes, yes dad, that's my dream.
杰森∶迈克,梦想就是给那些整天睡觉的人的.
Jason: Mike, dreams are for guys who don't get out of bed all day.
迈克∶说的真好.
Mike: Perfect.
杰森∶迈克,不,这个不完美,你所需要的是计划.
Jason: Mike, no, that is not perfect, what you need is a plan.
迈克∶为什么我的梦想就不能是我的计划呢?
Mike: Yeah, well, why can't my dream be my plan?
本∶恩,会是一个很长时间的教训吗,迈克?
BEN: Uhm, is this going to be a long reading Mike?
迈克∶我不知道,爸爸,你认为呢,20分钟?
Mike: I don't know, dad what do you think, like 20 minutes?
杰森∶本,出去,这不是教训.
Jason: Ben, get out...this is not a reading.
(电话响起)
(Phone rings)
麦琪,你可以接电话吗?我正在教训迈克.
Maggie will you get that?I'm reading Mike.
迈克∶哦,那你还说了什么谎话?
Mike: Oh well, what else have you lied about?
杰森∶迈克,你什么时候才会开始考虑你的未来呢?我是说,有时,我跟你谈话的时候,我会觉得好像还是在和玩医生与安哥拉游戏的幼儿园时的你在讨论.
Jason: Mike, when are you going to think about your future?I mean sometimes I
talk to you, I feel like I'm still talking to that kid who in kinder
garden played doctor with Angela modelucioni
迈克:治好了她的感冒,不是么?
Mike: Cured her cold, didn't I?
麦琪∶杰森,你的电话,从天堂打过来的,科罗拉多.
Maggie: Phones for you Jason, somebody from paradise, Colorado
杰森∶科罗拉多?
Jason: Colorado?
麦琪∶不必担心,不是我们付钱的.
Maggie: Don't worry, it's not collect.
杰森∶你能不能接管一下迈克?
Jason: Can you take over with Mike please?
妈妈∶他怎么了?没有做懒鬼?
Mom: So what was he doing?Don't be a bum?
迈克∶不,计划你的未来.
Mike: No, planning your future.
麦琪∶他说到哪里了?
Maggie: How far was he?
迈克∶他的左眼皮要跳了.
Mike: The vein over his left eye was starting to pulse.
杰森∶乔治叔叔...
Jason: Uncle George...
妈妈∶打电话来的是他?当他遗弃哈里阿姨,
Mom: SO that's who's calling?
当他遗弃整个家庭的时候,
Face it, when he walked out on aunt Harried,
他怎么会这么绝?告诉那个懒鬼让他去死.
he walked out on the whole family.Tell that bum to drop dead.
杰森∶太迟了,他已经死了.
Jason: Too late, he already ha s.
迈克∶那他怎么会打电话来?
Mike: Then, how did he call?
杰森∶我不知道是否可以,但是因为我有你的电话号码,
Jason: Well I don't know if I can,
所以我会让你知道的,好的.
but I have your number so I will let you know, yeah.
麦琪∶亲爱的,
Maggie: Honey I didn't mean to say he SHOULD drop dead,
我不是说他应该死,我相信他肯定有很好的理由去做那些自私而又残忍的事情,
I'm sure he had a good reason for being selfish rotten and deserting his
祝他安息.
wife...may he rest in peace.
杰森∶葬礼后天在他的小木屋里举行.
Jason: Well the funeral's the day after tomorrow at his cabin.
麦琪∶我们会送花过去.
Maggie: We will send flowers.
杰森∶不,他的律师说需要我们出席.
Jason: No, his lawyer says they want me there.
麦琪∶为什么?
Maggie: Why?
杰森∶乔治叔叔显然在他的遗嘱里写明我是负责人了.
Jason: Well.Uncle George apparently in his will named me executor.
迈克∶他都已经死了,还要负责人干什么?
Mike: What does he need an executing for if he's already dead?
杰森∶迈克,意思是说我负责执行他的遗愿,
Jason: Mike, It means that I'm in charge of carrying out his last wishes,
确保一切都进行的准确.
making sure it's done correctly.
麦琪∶但是为什么是你?你已经好几年没有和他有任何的联系了.
Maggie: But why you?You haven't talked to him in years.
杰森∶我也不知道.
Jason: I haven't the slightest idea.
迈克∶等等,乔治叔叔是不是就是那个每年给我们发自制的圣诞卡,
Mike: Wait a minute is this Uncle George guy the guy who used to send
而你们从来不回的那个人?
us homemade Christmas cards every year, but you never sent him anything?
妈妈∶我认为没有必要对一个不负责任的,
Mom: I see no reason to pretend I'm fond of irresponsible bums,
宁愿毁坏生活也不要工作的懒鬼假装我对他的喜爱.
who choose to rot his life away rather than work.
迈克∶但是,你却喜欢我.
Mike: But, you're fond of me.
杰森∶已经有15年了,为什么是我?
Jason: It's been 15 years Ma ggie...Why me?
麦琪∶杰森,他做的没有一件事情是有道理的.
Maggie: Jason, nothing he did ever made any sense.
杰森∶我们不了解.
Jason: We don't know that.
麦琪∶那他为什么要在他们刚刚付了漂亮房子的首付的时候离开哈里阿姨?
Maggie: Well then why did he leave aunt Harried the very month they made
the down payment on that beautiful home?
杰森∶我不知道.
Jason: I don't know.
麦琪∶那他为什么离开他自己的办事处?
Maggie: And why did he walk away from his own add agency?
迈克∶等等,他就是那个过去经常把我放在膝盖上弹跳,
Mike: Hey wait a minute,
还会一直对我说,"这是点心,
is this the guy who used to bounce me on his lap and say: "it's a
这是泻药,2个都是"之类的话的人.
pastry, it's a laxative, stop!Your both right"
杰森∶就是他.
Jason: That was him.
迈克∶爸爸,也许他会留给你一大笔钱,
Mike: Dad, maybe he's leaving you a ton of money,
这样你就可以不必工作,整天和我一起闲晃了.
and then you can quit your job and hang out with me.
杰森∶不,我不这样认为.
Jason: No I don't think so Mike; old aunt Harried bled him pretty good,
迈克,哈里阿姨用非常公正的方式把他的钱都花完了.
in a very just settlement.
杰森∶你有没有给我星期四所有的病人打电话,重新预约?
Jason: Ok, you've called all my Thursday patients for rescheduling?
凯文∶是的,但是除了霍泊先生以外.
Kevin: Sure, everybody but Mr.Hobs
杰森∶恩,他很害怕能响的东西.要不这样吧,凯文,等我早晨到了那里之后,就打电话告诉你那里的号码,这样你就可以打电话...
Jason: Of course, his fear of things that ring.Well, I think that's about it Kevin, I'm going to phone you in the morning as soon as I land with a number that you can call...
凯文∶在紧急情况下.….
Kevin: Incase there are any emergencies
杰森∶是的,回来的航班...
Jason: Yes, oh and the return flight...
凯文∶你应该来得及参加星期5,9点的会话吧?
Kevin: Should have you back Friday in time for your 9am session.
杰森∶我想我...
Jason: I guess I...
凯文∶已经说过...可以了...
Kevin: Already said that...yes...
杰森∶恩,10点.我要走了,
Jason: OK, yes, 10 o clock.I got to go...
凯文,不知道要怎么感谢你,今晚加班到现在?
Kevin how can I thank you for working late tonight.
凯文∶让我冒充一下当一个心理学家,然后吊几个女孩...
Kevin: By letting me pretend to be a psychiatrist and having some babes
开玩笑.
up here.Joke...
杰森∶好了,迈克,你在哪里,飞机在2个小时就要起飞了...
Jason: All right, Mike, come on, where are you, the plane leaves in two hours...
迈克∶对不起我来迟了..
Mike: Hey sorry I'm late dad...
杰森∶拿着那个...谢谢你能和我一起去,因此我们可以把乔治叔叔的遗物打包回来.
Jason: Yeah, well, take that...thank you for coming along with me so we can pack up uncle Georges belongings.
迈克∶噢,没问题,如果你付给我最低工资,我会很感激的
Mike: Uh, no problem, I appreciate you paying me minimum wage.
杰森∶嗨!尽我所能.
Jason: Hey, the least I could do.
迈克∶我知道.
Mike: I know
杰森∶我告诉你,如果所有的关系都往这个方向发展的话,
Jason: I tell you, if this is the way all the connections are going to go,
我敢肯定星期五早上都回不来.
im not even going to make it back by Friday morning.
迈克∶哦,爸爸,我们的飞机起飞晚了几分钟.
Mike: Oh come on dad, our plane took off a few minutes late.
杰森∶说对了.
Jason: Exactly.
迈克∶爸爸,冷静点,不要这么紧张.
Mike: Dad, come on chill out.Don't be so anal.
杰森∶什么?
Jason: What?
迈克∶不必担心,不是你想的那样.是一个心理学的术语.
Mike: Don't worry; it's not what you think.It's a psychological term.
杰森∶不是你这样用的.
Jason: Not the way you use it.
迈克∶爸爸,我们星期五一定要回来吗?
Mike: Dad, do we have to be back by Friday?
杰森∶迈克,你还是不知道责任意味着什么.
Jason: Mike you just don't know what its like to have responsibilities.
迈克∶我当然知道...我明天也有课,
Mike: Sure I do...
但是你看见我担心过他们了吗?
hey I got classes tomorrow, and do you see me worrying about missing them?
杰森∶等等,你说过如果你跟我一起来的话,你不会落下任何课的.
Jason: Wait a minute; you said if you came with me, you wouldn't be missing any classes.
迈克∶我绝对不会落下任何一门.
Mike: And I won't miss a one of them
空姐∶耳机?
Stew Ardess: Headsets?
杰森∶不用,谢谢.
Jason: No, no thank you.
迈克∶爸爸,不过才几美元.
Mike: Dad come on, they are only a few bucks.
杰森∶从我上次的飞机上拿来的.
Jason: Here...from my last flight.
迈克∶爸爸,他们不匹配.
Mike: Dad, they don't fit the hole.
杰森∶试试这个.
Jason: Try this one
迈克∶爸爸,你还有多少副耳机?
Mike: Dad, how many more headsets you got in there?
杰森∶没有了.花生?啊哈,看...
Jason: None....Peanuts? AHA! Look at these....
玛莲∶是什么?
Mike: What's that?
杰森∶我的清单.
Jason: My list
迈克∶要做的事情的清单?
Mike: Of things to do?
杰森∶不,不,事实上这个只是我的附清单的主清单.
Jason: No.no.this is actually my master list of all my sub lists.
迈克∶好事情,你一点也不紧张.
Mike: Good thing you are not anal.
杰森∶你倒是提醒我了,我忘记告诉你妈妈,水管工人明天会来.
Jason: Jee, that reminds me, I forgot to tell your mother, the plumber is coming tomorrow.
迈克∶爸爸,别担心了,她会明白的,我是说当那个人带着滑阀出现的时候,妈妈难道还不会知道他是来干什么的吗?啊,让我有了一个想法.
Mike: Dad, come on she will figure it out, don't worry about it...I mean, she will figure it out when the guy shows up with a plunger.Ah, it gives me an idea.
杰森∶不,直到肯定后,我才标注出来.
Jason: No, I'm not highlighting this until I'm sure.
迈克∶爸爸,当我们上飞机的时候,
Mike: Dad, it's called an airphone...I saw it when we got on the plane.
我看见一种叫移动飞机电话的东西.你只要拨你的号码加上区域代码就可以和任何人说话.
You just dial in your number with the area code and you can reach anybody.
杰森∶这个东西要花多少钱?
Jason: How much does this thing cost?
迈克∶恩,开始30秒要15美元.
Mike: Uhm, 15 dollars for the first 30 seconds.
麦琪∶哈罗?
Maggie: Hello?
杰森∶麦琪,水管工人明天中午和3点钟之间会来,他是一个新手,
Jason: Maggie, the plumber is coming tomorrow sometime between noon and
但是,上次也是他负责的,
three, he's new but he's the last guy in charge, everything else is fine,
其他的事情都很好,我爱你,再见.
I love you, bye.
迈克∶哦!哇!!!
Mike: Oh wow!!!
杰森∶哦!超过了一点点.
Jason: Oh wow, later.
出租车司机∶我们已经到了,先生,我早就没打表了.
Taxi Driver: We've been wowed out sir, I turned the meter off.
杰森∶等一下,我只是刚刚想起来,
Jason: Wait a minute, it just occurred to me,
我没有钥匙打开箱子.
I don't have a key to this cabin.
出租车司机∶不需要,那是在纽约.
Taxi Driver: You won't need one, it's in new York.
杰森∶你来自于纽约?
Jason: You are from New York?
出租车司机∶我说你.
Taxi Driver: I called you.
杰森∶等一下,你是乔治叔叔的律师?
Jason: Wait a minute; you are Uncle George's lawyer?
出租车司机∶普雷波尔M.杰克逊先生,随时为您效劳.
Taxi Driver: Playbor M.Jackson Esquire, at your service.
杰森∶但是你是一个出租车司机.
Jason: But you are a cab driver.
出租车司机∶我也是镇长,不动产交易经纪人和电影评论家,
Taxi Driver: I'm also the town mayor, real estate broker and movie critic,
但是,我最喜欢的还是全身按摩.
but my first love will always be chiropracting.
迈克∶多棒的地方!
Mike: what a place.Wow
出租车司机∶他花了15年的时间来建造它,全手工的.
Taxi Driver: He spent 15 years building it...did it all by hand.
迈克∶根本不用工具?
Mike: No tools at all huh?
杰森∶杰克逊先生,既然你在已经在这里了,也许我们可以先看看遗嘱,这样我们就可以开始清理这个地方,然后我5点钟还要赶回家.
Jason: Listen Mr.Jackson, as long as you are here, maybe we can take a
look at the will now, that way we can get started cleaning up the place
and I'd make my 5pm departure back home
出租车司机∶你们是今天飞出来的?
Taxi Driver: You are flying out today?
杰森∶是的,我明天有很多病人在等着.
Jason: Oh yeah, I got a full load of patients tomorrow.
出租车司机∶恩...
Taxi Driver: Hmm...
杰森∶怎么了 ?
Jason: What's the matter?
出租车司机∶你的叔叔希望在他的葬礼结束后才公布他的遗嘱,如果那样的话,
Taxi Driver: Well, your uncle didn't want the will read until his funeral,
就要等到太阳下山.
and that's not until sunset.
杰森∶如果那样的话,我们就不可能在5点前离开这里了,
Jason: Oh but that wouldn't get me out of here by 5 o clock,
那我们就会赶不上飞机了,我的儿子非常渴望能马上回到大学...
I'd miss my plane, and my sons anxious to get back to college, you know...
迈克∶爸爸,我们可不可以多留几天?我爱这里.
Mike: Wow, dad, can we stay here a couple of extra days?I love this place.
杰森∶但是我所有的计划都是根据5点的离开而制定的.
Jason: But all of my plans are based on a 5pm departure.
出租车司机∶我知道怎么样保持你的日程.
Taxi Driver: Look I know how we can keep you on schedule.
杰森∶好的,好的,好的.
Jason: Good, good, good.
出租车司机∶好,只要我们忽略一个死人的要求,然后马上用水把他的骨灰冲进厕所.
Taxi Driver: Yeah, we will just ignore a dying mans request and flush his ashes down the toilet right now.
杰森∶我明白了.
Jason: I get the point.
出租车司机∶我也应该警告你,我还是镇上的愤世嫉俗者.
Taxi Driver: I should have warned you, I'm also the town cynic.
麦琪∶那是什么?
Maggie: What's that?
克莉丝∶南瓜.
Chrissy: Pumpkin.
麦琪∶对的.
Maggie: That's right.
麦琪∶哈罗?
Maggie: Hello?
杰森∶我的一天都搞砸了.
Jason: My entire day is ruined.
麦琪∶我很好啊,谢谢问候.
Maggie: I'm fine Jason thanks for asking.
杰森∶抱歉,宝贝儿,我只是很烦...
Jason: Sorry honey, I'm just upset.
麦琪∶哦,我也很烦.我半夜就被拍卖人吵醒,一大早水管工人就来了,还说我们有预约.
Maggie: Oh I'm upset too...I got woken up in the middle of the night by some auctioneer.And then early this morning this plumber showed up and claimed we had an appointment.
杰森∶你没有让他走?
Jason: You didn't send him away?
麦琪∶杰森,我怎么能打发一个6英尺1英寸的强壮的金发碧眼的男人走呢?
Maggie: Jason, why would I send a 6 foot 1 inch muscular blonde man away?
杰森∶我觉得你是在和我开玩笑呢..
Jason: I hear you are having fun with me...
麦琪∶不象我和道福之间那么有趣..
Maggie: Not as much fun as I had with Dolf
杰森∶我终于明白乔治叔叔为什么要离开哈里阿姨了.
Jason: I'm beginning to understand why Uncle George might have left aunt Harried.
麦琪∶杰森,我知道水管工人会来,
Maggie: Well Jason, I knew the plumber was coming,
因为我发现了枕头下的你的附清单.
I found your sub list under my pillow.
杰森∶亲爱的,我没心情,我要错过5点的飞机了.
Jason: Honey please, I'm in no mood, I'm going to miss my 5 o clock flight.
麦琪:为什么?
Maggie: Why?
杰森∶我也不知道,我也不知道我为什么要来这里.
Jason: I don't even know, I don't even know why I'm here.
麦琪∶杰森,放松.好好的享受你的休息世界...你平时工作太累了.
Maggie: Jason, just relax...enjoy the time off...you work too hard as it is.
杰森∶说起来容易...一切都有条有理.
Jason: That's easy for you to say...your whole world is in order.
麦琪∶不,我说这些是因为我正在给道福准备三明治,"
Maggie: no, I just said that because I'm fixing Dolf a sandwich. "Maggie,
麦琪,我的火腿上不要放芥末".
I don't want mustard on my wiener"
杰森∶宝贝,我不得不说,和你的谈话让我感觉更加糟糕.
Jason: Well sweetheart, I got to say that having this little chat with you has made me feel worse.
麦琪∶我也爱你宝贝.
Maggie: I love you too sweetheart.
杰森∶好了,吻克莉丝,再见,爱你.
Jason: All right, kiss Chrissy, bye-bye, love you.
妈妈∶爱你,再见.
Mom: Love you, bye
迈克∶爸爸,外面发生了很严重的事情.
Mike: Dad, there is some serious nature happening outside this place.
杰森∶知道了,我还有几个电话要打,迈克.
Jason: All right, well, I got some calls here to make Mike.
迈克:爸爸,跟你说我刚刚看到了一只熊,
Mike: Dad, I'm telling you I just saw this bear, a big one,
一只大熊,长着一只鹿角.
with antlers up to here.
杰森∶现在是白天,你不要再做梦了.
Jason: You know, its daylight, shouldn't you be sleeping?
迈克∶爸爸.是真的,我一点都不累.我是说如果乔治叔叔安装了一个卫星接收器的话,那么这里就是一个生活的首选之地.
Mike: Dad, It is wield , I am not even tired here.I mean, if Uncle George had only put in a satellite dish, this would be a primo place to live.
杰森∶我要打几个电话.不好意思,我很忙.
Jason: Look, I got some calls, sorry I'm busy.
迈克∶好了,不要再想你的清单了.
Mike: Come on, forget about your lists all right?
你觉得我们去杀几只野味来吃吃,怎么样?
Come on what do you say we go kill something and eat it?
女人∶抱歉,我正在找....是你!
Woman: Excuse me, I'm looking for.....YOU!
杰森∶我?我们见过吗?
Jason: Me?Have we met?
女人∶一点点.你的照片被挂在卧室.
Woman: In a way.Your picture is in the bedroom.
是一张很旧的照片,但是不管你有没有连鬓胡子我都能认出你.
It's an old picture, but I'd know you with or without those sideburns
杰森∶哈哈,你是?
Jason: Haha, and you are?
南茜艾西顿:抱歉,我是南茜艾西顿.
Nancy Ashton: Oh, I'm sorry, I'm Nancy Ashton.I was your Uncle Georges L....
是你乔治叔叔的...朋友.
Friend.Those three years we had together,
我们在一起的这3年是我人生当中最快乐的3年,
were the happiest years I've ever had.
对不起,我保证过不再哭的.
I'm sorry, I promised my self I wouldn't do this.
杰森:没关系.
Jason: It's ok.
南茜∶乔治是世界上最善良,最会照顾人,最棒的男人,但是你知道吗,你是他最喜欢的外甥.
Nancy: George was the kindest, most caring, most wonderful man in the world, but you know that...I mean...you were his favorite nephew.
杰森∶我是吗?
Jason: I was?
南茜∶我会给你看的.
Nancy: I'll show you.
迈克∶爸爸,我想我们总算搞清楚了.
Mike: Dad, I think I got this figured out.
这里肯定不是死去的乔治叔叔的小木屋.
We are at the wrong dead Uncle Georges cabin.
杰森∶迈克,我带你来是搬东西的,不是思考的.
Jason: Mike I brought you here to carry things, not to think.
迈克∶爸爸,你想想,她所说的那么好的男人怎么可能会抛弃他的妻子呢?
Mike: Dad, come on, how could this wonderful guy she's talking about be the same rotten guy who deserted his wife?
南茜∶你看!!!
Nancy: Here!!!
杰森∶这是什么?
Jason: What are these?
南茜∶在过去的15年里每年给你的圣诞卡.
Nancy: Oh, every Christmas card you sent him for the past 15 years.
杰森:哦,我不知道.
Jason: Oh, I had no idea.
南茜∶哦!抱歉,
Nancy: Oh, I'm sorry, I forgot why I came...
我忘了自己来这里的目的了,我带来了一些食物,在车里.
I brought some food, it's in the car.
迈克∶爸爸,我想妈妈从来没有给他寄过任何圣诞卡!
Mike: Dad, I thought that mom didn't send him any Christmas cards...
杰森∶她没有....
Jason: well, she didn't.
杰克逊先生(出租车司机)∶现在我们言归正转.大家都来跟乔治叔叔最爱的外甥杰森西维尔打个招呼.
Mr.Jackson (TAXI DRIVER): Now let's get down to business.Everyone say hi to Uncle George's favorite nephew, Jason Seaver
所有人∶现在我只是照着他所写的来读."
Everybody: Hi Ok now I'm going to read this just the way he wrote it. "
我,
I George Washington Bomber,
乔治华盛顿,在我精神正常的情况下制定了我的临终遗嘱.
being of sound mind -at least I always thought so- leave this my last
现在我想要把我所有的东西都留给我亲爱的南茜.
will and testament.Now I wanted to leave everything to my beloved Nancy.
南茜∶不不要!!
Nancy: No don't!!
杰克逊先生∶坐下,南茜,我会尊重你的愿望,
Mr.Jackson: Sit down Nancy I'm going to honor your wishes,
为了这么多年的美好时光,她不是很美吗?我看过了并且也同意这样做.
that's for the wonderful
year...isn't she pretty...I read that but I have to agree
至于我心爱的外甥杰森西维尔,小木屋,
To my beloved nephew Jason Seaver I leave the Cabin and the three or four
还有3英亩或是四英亩地,普内泊尔从来都没有跟我说清楚他卖给我的是什么,撒谎的贼.
acres, Playbor never made it clear exactly what he sold me, the lying thief.
好了,我看过并且同意这样做.
Well, I read that and I have to agree with that too.
迈克∶你跟他说什么了?
Mike: What did you tell him?
杰森∶我忘记了.
Jason: I forget.
杰克逊先生∶对于在纽约的家人和朋友,我只想留下以下我的几点想法:我不后悔离开纽约,
Mr.Jackson: To old family and friends in New York,
我也不后悔追求梦想.
I'd like to leave you with the following thoughts:
我但愿所有的人都能明白,不是每个人都适合去过计划好的和规定好的生活,
I don't regret my decision to leave New York,
就想房子按揭一样.
I don't regret my decision to follow a dream.
对此,我很抱歉.
I wish people had understood,
但是我这样说,并没有任何的恶意,
not everybody is cut out for a life that's planned and regulated as a
事实上我只希望每个人都能找到乐趣和满足,
monthly house bill.Sorry about that.
就像这些年来我找到的一样,尤其是哈里,
But I bare no one here ill will,
嫁给我是你的不幸.
in fact I hope everyone finds the joy and contentment I found over these
所以丢下你的手帕,过的开心点...
years, especially Harriet, who had the misfortune to marry me.
是一个葬礼...
So put away your handkerchiefs and enjoy yourselves...
也是一个聚会.2个都是!!
It's a funeral,,, it's a party!!!Shot...you're both right!!!
迈克∶爸爸怎么回事?
Mike: Dad what is going on?
杰森∶我也不知道.
Jason: I have no idea.
迈克∶爸爸,除非你有一些很有意义和重要的东西...
Mike: Oh come on think dad,
我是说好像不像是你说了什么健康的,
unless you have something meaningful and important...
重要的,和有意义的话.
I mean it's not like you say important and meaningful things are healthy.
杰森∶对不起,我没有意识到会有别人在这里.
Jason: I'm sorry, I didn't realize anybody else was out here.
南茜∶没关系,你可以留下来.我知道乔治会希望我们在这里开心的度过,但是,看上去有点困难.
Nancy: Oh that's all right, you can stay.I know that George would want us in there having fun, but well, it's a little tough.
杰森∶是的.南茜,我知道问你这个问题会让我很尴尬,但是,请问你是否知道我到底跟他说了什么重要的话?
Jason: Yes yes it is.Nancy I'm a little embarrassed to even ask but do you have any idea of what I might have said that meant so much to George?
南茜∶你不知道?你真的不知道.你告诉他...
Nancy: You don't know?You really don't know.Well, you told him that....
迈克∶驼鹿肉真是太好吃了.
Mike: The minced moose meet is marvelous.
南茜∶我正要告诉你爸爸,他跟乔治叔叔说了什么.
Nancy: I was just telling your dad what he told your Uncle George.
迈克∶哦!天哪!我也很想知道.
Mike: Oh oh Gosh.Well, I'd love to hear it too.
南茜∶你对他说:没有梦想的生活有什么意义呢?
Nancy: You said to him: What's your life without your dreams?
迈克∶这个男人这样说?
Mike: This man said this?
你肯定不是:没有清单的生活又有什么意义呢?
You sure it wasn't: What's your life without your lists?
南茜∶我肯定.你还跟他说,
Nancy: I'm sure.You also said that staying open to possibilities is so
保持进可能的开明比对每件事和每个行动都做计划要重要的多.
much more important than planning every move or watching every dime.
杰森∶我忘记了.
Jason: I had forgotten.
迈克∶我来对了小木屋,却找错了父亲.
Mike: I got the right Cabin, just the wrong father.
杰克逊先生∶南茜,一切都好了吗?
Mr.Jackson: Nancy, everything all right?
杰森∶好了,好了,我很好.进来吧,好好享受聚会.
Jason: Oh yeah yeah, No, I'm fine...go on in, have a good party, enjoy it.
杰克逊先生∶抱歉,
Mr.Jackson: Excuse me Jason, as your Uncle George's attorney and friend;
杰森作为你乔治叔叔的律师和朋友,我非常感谢你们能来.
I want to thank you for making the trip.
作为你们的出租车司机,
As your cab driver I want to remind you I will be picking you up at 6
我要提醒你们,我会在明天早上6点来接你们.
am tomorrow.Too bad you couldn't stick around a couple more days and help
很抱歉你们不能多留几天来帮忙完成小木屋.
finish up the cabin.
杰森∶你的话是什么意思?
Jason: What are you talking about?
杰克逊先生∶当他离开的时候,他正在准备安装烟囱帽.
Mr.Jackson: Well, George was just fixing to lay up the chimney top when
作为你的不动产交易经纪人,这些都不会影响他的价值.
he passed away.But as your real estate broker, it won't affect the price.
作为一个按摩师,你不应该这么驼背.
As a chiropractor, you shouldn't hunch over like that.
迈克∶嘿爸爸,你真的是如那位女士所说的那样吗?
Mike: Hey dad, are you really like that lady said?
杰森∶噢,很早以前.
Jason: Uh, longtime ago.
迈克:你是说你不是经常...
Mike: You mean so you weren't always so ....
杰森∶直肠的?
Jason: Anal?
迈克∶对...
Mike: ok...
杰森∶迈克,曾经有过那么一段时间,我根本就不用做任何的清单.
Jason: Mike, there was a time I didn't even make any lists.
迈克:不可能.
Mike: Oh get out of here.
杰森∶不,是真的.曾经有一个夏天,你妈妈和我靠搭便车而穿过了整个国家.
Jason: No, its true, you know your mom and I one summer, we hitchhiked right across this country.
迈克∶她怎么样梳头发的?
Mike: Ho did she do her hair?
杰森∶你妈妈那时比现在要轻...我们也在想这样在星星下露宿.
Jason: Yeah, your mom was a lot looser than too... We just camped out under the stars like this.
迈克∶那你们时候开始变的有条理了?
Mike: Yeah? So when did you start going down hill?
杰森∶在你出生不久后.
Jason: Soon after you were born.
迈克∶我明白了,都是我的错.
Mike: I see, So It's all my fault.
杰森∶不是,只是...一旦你有了孩子后,就很难活得那么自在了.
Jason: No, it's just...well once you have kids; I guess it's tough to be one.
但是看看这个,迈克...想像一下,
But look at this Mike...
住在这里,呼吸这样的空气,每天晚上看星星...是一件多么惬意的事情!
Imagine living out here, breathing this air, seeing these stars every night?
迈克∶爸爸,现在这个地方是你的了,你想做什么就做什么.
Mike: Dad, I mean, look, you own this place, you could do whatever you want.
杰森∶你变得现实了.
Jason: nah, you got to be realistic.
迈克∶你和妈妈在这里暂时的过一段时间,有什么不现实的呢?
Mike: oh come on dad, what is not realistic about you and mom spending a little time out here?
杰森∶如果你妈妈在这里的话,"麦琪,我回来了"..你打到了驼鹿肉了吗?
Jason: Yeah right...You see your mother out here? "Hi Maggie I'm home" ... Did you get the moose meat?
迈克:我是说,
Mike: Yeah I just mean that, I don't know,
也许你不应该卖掉这个地方.
maybe you shouldn't sell this place.
杰森∶我的生活在纽约.
Jason: My life is in New York
迈克∶但是...
Mike: But...
杰森∶谈话结束.
Jason: End of conversation
迈克∶我只是认为太糟糕了,
Mike: I just think it's too bad you don't have someone talking to you
居然没有一个像乔治叔叔那样简朴的人来和你说心里话.
like that neat guy uncle George did.
杰森:纽约也有同样的星星……只是我们看不到.
Jason: We have the same stars in New York you know...We just cant see them.
迈克∶天空正在塌下来.
Mike: The sky is falling.
杰森∶对不起的迈克…
Jason: Sorry Mike...
迈克∶爸爸?
Mike: Dad?
杰森∶快上来,爬上来.
Jason: Up here, come on up
迈克∶不,谢谢,我宁愿睡觉.
Mike: No thanks, I'd rather sleep.
杰森∶你过来帮我把这个石头搬一下..
Jason: You come up or ill drop another rock...
迈克∶爸爸,你到底在做什么?
Mike: Dad, what the heck are you doing?
杰森∶什么?你的样子让人觉得你好像从来没见过你爸爸在日出的时候做泥瓦工一样.
Jason: What? Come on you act like you have never seen your dad do masonry at sunrise.
迈克∶哈!?
Mike: huh?
杰森∶过来帮我.
Jason: Come up and give me a hand.
迈克∶爸爸,我们必须在1个小时内赶到机场.
Mike: dad, we got to be in the airport in less than an hour.
杰森∶迈克,这些差不多也只要一个多小时,我不想慌慌张张的,我想先把这个做好.
Jason: Well, it will just take a little longer than that mike, I don't want to hurry, I want to get this right.
迈克∶但是飞机...
Mike: But the plane...
杰森∶迈克,还会有别的航班的,给你一块石头.
Jason: Mike, there will be other flights Come on, give me a rock.
迈克∶爸爸,你是不是不小心从屋顶摔下来了,摔坏了你的脑子?
Mike: Dad, did you by chance fall of the roof and land on your head?
杰森∶我昨晚开始想,在你妈妈来这里之前,把这个小木屋修好,可能是一件很美好的事情.
Jason: I just started thinking last night; I think it would be nice to have a finished cabin by the time your mother comes up here.
迈克∶那她什么时候会来?
Mike: well when is she coming up?
杰森:我不知道,我不知道,
Jason: I don't know, I don't know, maybe a vacation...
也有会有个假期,我还没有计划好.
I haven't made a plan yet.
迈克∶但是爸爸,我以为你要把这里卖了呢.
Mike: But dad, I thought you were selling this place.
杰森∶你也认为我很吝啬.杰森西维尔,他是一个成年人,
Jason: Yeah, well you also thought I was cheap.
他是一个梦想家.住口.两者都是.
Jason Seaver, he's an adult, he's a dreamer.Stop.You are both caught.
迈克∶好!!!
杰森∶简直是不敢相信从这里看下去的景色...你看过了吗?
00:22:22,300
Mike: All right!!! Jason: Can't believe this view up here... Did you look around?